REVATHY A/P SANKARAN

Nationality: Malaysian

No. 56A Jalan Permai 3, Taman Perkota, 75350, Melaka.

Mobile Number: 014-6307008 Email: revathysankaran@ymail.com



CAREER PROFILE

Highly enthusiastic and determined science graduate with a passion in biotechnology. Possess excellent analytical and research skills coupled with solid teamwork abilities. Ambitious, competent and dedicated in going the extra mile to master the skills needed to make a positive contribution.

EDUCATION

• Bachelor of Science Majoring in Biotechnology, University Malaysia Sarawak (2013)

CORE SUBJECTS

- Food Biotechnology
- Enzymology
- Bioprocess Technology
- Cell and Tissue Culture
- Plant and Animal Biotechnology
- Virology and Immunology
- Recombinant DNA Technology
- Microbiology

- Cell Biology
- Medical Biotechnology
- Field Techniques in Biotechnology
- Genetics
- Biochemistry
- Social Issue in Biotechnology
- Plant Physiology
- Natural Resource Management and Legislation

FINAL YEAR PROJECT

Title: Biochemical Identification of an Alkalophilic Lactic Acid Bacterium & Testing its Fermentative Capacity.

- Conducted biochemical test using API 20 kit to identify the isolated bacterium.
- Performed fermentation using two different pH values to test the fermentative capability of the isolated bacterium.
- Underwent extensive reading and analysis of 50 reference materials.
- Identified and solved complex problem during performing the project.
- Worked and assisted laboratory members when required.

Findings: Successfully identified the isolated bacterium as *Enterococcus faecalis*. The growth of biomass and LA production for *Enterococcus faecalis* are influenced by the pH and the optimum pH for this strain was found to be at pH8.

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Participant in GEMS Excel Minds Program (2014)

- Headed and planed presentation for business planning activity in the program.
- Collaborated with group members in finishing task given on time.

Secretary of Security and Discipline Department in Collage Residential Association (2013)

- Ensured planned events were carried out smoothly.
- Prepared minute of meetings.
- Developed effective working relationship with team members in conducting events.

Committee Member of Photography Club (2012)

- Supported the organization in a major event.
- Set up booth to promote others to join this club.

Member in Indian Culture Society (2010-2011)

• Supported the club in organizing a major event.

Seed of Hope Campaign (2011)

• Appointed Narrator for the Seed of Hope Campaign.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Melaka Biotechnology Corporation

(June 2012– August 2012)

Research Assistant in Molecular Department (Internship)

- Performed DNA extraction from food sample to obtain its DNA.
- Prepared gel electrophoresis to analyse DNA.
- Analysed DNA extracted to identify halal food.
- Carried out DNA extraction of "Kesum" leaf to obtain its DNA profile.

Melaka Mydin Supermarket

(June 2011-August 2011)

Customer Service

- Assisted customer to renew Mydin's member card.
- Provided help to customer when required.
- Checked returned or spoilt items purchased by customer before refunding money.
- Managed short accounts for balancing.

Advocate Mogan Karupiah's Law Firm Typist

(May 2011- June2011)

- Typed court papers for clients.
 - Organized court hearing papers.

SKILLS AND STRENGTHS

Teamwork Skill – Able to work within a team in completing various laboratory projects and assisted team members when required.

Analytical & Research Skills – Gathered sufficient information in performing FYP. Evaluated and analysed data obtained in providing a conclusion for the project.

Communication & Interpersonal Skills – Built effective working relationship with team members in conducting projects during "Collage Residential Day".

Language Skills – Excellent Bahasa Malaysia, Excellent English, Fair Tamil.

Lab Skills – Mass Spectrometer, Glucose and ethanol analyser, Centrifuge machines.

REFERENCES

Referees: Associate Professor DR. Cirilo Nolasco Hipolito, Lecturer UNIMAS, 013-8134163.

Referees: Abdah Azzuhdina bt Amin, Research Officer, 017-6697656.